Resume

Name: Roni Sar

Address:vill+p.o-charkalgram,dist -Birbhum,West Bengal,731301

Email Id:. ronisarwb@gmail.com

Contact No. 7430035584

I possess 7 years of experience in the field of culinary arts, having worked at various renowned properties in India. My expertise lies in the field of Modern Indian food with a traditional touch. I am equipped to perform under duress and make good quality food, high in taste, within a stipulated time period. I have trained under various chefs in order to expertise in quality check procedures and regulations to be followed. I perform equally well in banquet style large scale cooking.

Objective:

To utilize my abilities and experience of managing a team making special variety dishes of different place in a professional rewarding environment.

Education:

- ** I have completed my 10th from wbsc board in 2009
- ** I have completed my 12th from whhse board in 2011
- ** I also have some basis knowledge in computers

Achievements and skills:

- ** Have the ability and experience to prepare quality variety dishes in the stipulated time.
- ** Have expertise in variety of techniques in cooking to prepare healthy tasty dishes
- ** Have experience of managing all operations related to dish in star hotels.
- ** Have also trained team mates, by conducting practical and training cooking classes.
- ** Have got many appreciation and certification, for making excellent new delicious dishes.
- ** Ambitious to work in a challenging environment, requiring constant development of fresh skills and to utilize existing skills to the maximum.

Strengths:

- ** Prepare healthy and delicious dishes for large crowds (banquets)
- ** Efficient to make a quality food to attract customers (a-la carte)
- ** Efficient in cost control while preparing quality healthy food and thereby gives profit to the organization as well as satisfying customers
- ** Team player, Hard worker, Fast Learner, Confident and a go-getter
- ** Excellent communication and interpersonal skills
- ** Specialization in Indian (Curry)food
- ** Modern religion food
- ** To lift heavy weights as required from time to time

Work History:

- ** At present working at LEMON TREE PREMIER, Kolkata since December 2019 as CDP Indian (curry) 2019. Responsibilities:
- * Handle events of medium to large size held in venue as it is a star venue, I have to deliver the quality food and in proper order.
- * Maintain the budget of the kitchen and handle the Curry section of venue. In my section I have to cook Chicken, mutton, fish, and all stock for soup /shorba. But my specialization is in North Indian food.
- *Maintain logs and data as required by hotel rules and regulations.
- * Prepare store list on the database.
- * Report to the sous chef and the executive sous chef about all requirements of the department.
- ** Worked at THE FERN SAMALI RESORT (star venue) as commi 1st + DCDP form November 2018

Responsibilities:

- * Handle events of medium to large size held in venue as it is a star venue, I have to deliver the quality food and in proper order.
- * Maintain the budget of the kitchen and handle the Curry section of venue. In my section I had to cook Chicken, mutton, fish, and all stock for soup /shorba. But my specialization is in North Indian food.

February 2018 to October 2018:

AMBER SAROVAR PORTICO(Star) work as commi 1

Responsibilities:

- * I used to make different type of biryanis, stock and gravy for chicken, mutton and veg(red, yellow,brown& White) gravy.
- * I also maintained temperatures books.
- * To make menu and maintain the kitchen budget.
- * Handel all the expected responsibilities in absence of head chef . Work in a team and bind the team together and have to see all the part of kitchen.

February 2017 to February 2018:

THE RED MAPLE MASHAL HOTEL(4star)- commi2+commi1

Worked to help in Indian section and closing kitchen after dinner. .

NEXUS CLUB &CONVENTION CENTER(GANDHIDHAM, GUJARAT)

Nov 2015 - February 2017 : Commi 2

Responsibilities:

- * I took the responsibility of managing and delivering quality delicious food. Specialized in presenting delicious vegetarian/non veg. food. I use to work on pan. I was responsible for making gravy and curry.
- * I specialized in making Break Fast and lunch &dinner.

PIYUS PALACE hotel, Ahmedabad, Gujrat

December 2014 to November 2015- Commi3

I took the responsibility of delivering proper order and helped senior chefs and followed their instructions.

MAHAMAYA RESTAURANT, West Bengal

May 2014 to November, Commi3,

Here I was learning how take responsibility in kitchen operations. Basic kitchen etiquettes, process of making food, etc.

Name: Roni Sar Date: 26/02/2021